関係者[かんけいしゃ]:authorized people/authorised people/person(s) concerned
（ヤサコ）関係者のウワサによると
According to rumors among informed people,
イマーゴ:imago, 電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 医療[いりょう]:medical care/medical treatment, 深い[ふかい]:deep|profound|dense||, 関わり[かかわり]:relation/connection
イマーゴと電脳医療には
深い関わりがあるそうです
there is a deep connection between Imago and Cybercures.
（フミエ）あっ… デンスケ
Densuke!
京子！
（フミエ）待って
Kyoko!
Wait!
そんな…
But that's...!
まさか:by no means/never!|something unexpected, さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
これって まさか さっきの話の…
Maybe it's related to the story we just heard?
バ… バカなこと言わないで
Stop talking nonsense!
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 外す[はずす]:to unfasten|to remove|to leave|
まずは メガネを外したほうが…
First of all, we'd better take her glasses off...
Wait!
（ヤサコ）待って！
We mustn't...
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 外す[はずす]:to unfasten|to remove|to leave|
メガネを… メガネを外しちゃダメ
We mustn't take her glasses off.
イリーガル:illegal
あ… あなたたち イリーガル？
A-Are you... Illegals?
ヤバい:dangerous|awful|terrific
ヤサコ こいつらヤバいわよ
Yasako,
they're dangerous.
ねえ なんで こんなことするの？
Why are you doing this?
返す[かえす]:to return (something)|to turn over|to pay back|
京子を返して！
Give Kyoko back!
逃げる[にげる]:to escape/to run away
逃げるのよ！
Let's run!
The Black Visitors
どうしよう 京子が…
What should we do? Kyoko is...
京子ちゃんなら
そこにいるじゃない
Kyoko is right here, isn't she!
でも…
But...
外[そと, と]:outside|open air|other place, 外[ほか]:other (place, thing, person)|outside|nothing except|
とにかく 外に出るわよ
Anyway, let's get out of here.
Damn, how many of them are there?
匹[ひき, き]:counter for small animals|counter for rolls of cloth (two han in size)|counter for horses|
こいつら 何匹いるのよ
ああっ…
（フミエ）こっちよ
This way!
京子…
Kyoko...
メタタグ:META tag
もうメタタグがないわ
I've run out of metatags.
デンスケ！
Densuke!
That's Mega-baa's barrier.
結界[けっかい]:(fixing) boundaries for religious practices|prohibition (of items, people, spirits, etc. that would hinder Buddhist practice)|fence between inner and outer sanctums in a temple||
メガばあの結界だわ
It seems they can't enter.
入れる[いれる]:to put in|to admit|to accept||, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
（ヤサコ）入れないみたい
There are some outside too.
外[そと, と]:outside|open air|other place, 外[ほか]:other (place, thing, person)|outside|nothing except|
外にもいるようね
Who knows what the Megashi store is like in these conditions!
屋[や]:(something) shop|somebody who sells (something) or works as (something)|somebody with a (certain) personality trait||
これじゃあ
メガシ屋も分からないわ
There's a lot of tags in here too.
かなり:considerably/fairly/quite, 貼る[はる]:to stick|to stretch|to form (e.g. ice on a pond)||
中にも かなり貼ってある
We're safe, thanks to the Mega-baa's thorough precautions.
用心[ようじん]:care/precaution/guarding, 深い[ふかい]:deep|profound|dense||, 救う[すくう]:to rescue from/to help out of/to save
メガばあの用心深さに救われたわ
Yeah...
Someone once told me...
ある人に聞いたの
In the deepest part of obsolete Space,
古い[ふるい]:old (not person)/aged/ancient, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 深い[ふかい]:deep|profound|dense||, 所[ところ, とこ]:place|address|district||, 所[しょ]:counter for places, 危険[きけん]:danger/peril|risk, イリーガル:illegal
古い空間の深い所には
危険なイリーガルがいるって
there are dangerous Illegals.
That's just bogus.
全部[ぜんぶ]:all/entire/whole, インチキ:cheating/fraud/trickery
全部インチキよ
Because of what you said,
あんな:such (about something or someone distant from both speaker and listener, or about a situation unfamiliar to both speaker and listener)/so/that, あんな:Anna or Anwa era (968.8.13-970.3.25), 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
ヤサコがあんな話するからさ
I ended up running for real.
本気[ほんき]:seriousness/earnestness/truth, 逃げる[にげる]:to escape/to run away
私も つい
本気で逃げちゃったじゃない
How silly.
寝る[ねる]:to lie down|to go to bed|to sleep (lying down)||
やあね…
京子ちゃんだって寝てるだけよ
Also, Kyoko is just sleeping.
Tomorrow morning, she...
朝[あさ, あした]:morning, 朝[ちょう]:dynasty|reign|period||
朝になれば…
んっ？　ヤサコ？
Yasako?
She's got a fever.
熱[ねつ]:heat|fever|zeal|
熱があるわ
No Space alterations found yet, huh?
空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 異変[いへん]:unusual phenomenon/unusual event/abnormal event, 見つかる[みつかる]:to be found/to be discovered
（イサコ）空間の異変は
まだ見つからないか
There's another unknown factor.
未知[みち]:not yet known/unknown/strange, 要因[よういん]:main cause/primary factor
（猫目(ねこめ)）
何か もう１つの未知の要因
The passage opens because of that trigger.
誘発[ゆうはつ]:cause/induce/lead up to, 通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||
それに誘発されて通路は開くんだ
Another factor...
未知[みち]:not yet known/unknown/strange, 要因[よういん]:main cause/primary factor
未知の要因？
通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 偶然[ぐうぜん]:coincidence|by chance|contingency (philosophy)
原川(はらかわ)が通路に入ったのは
偶然じゃない
The fact that Harakawa entered the passage
wasn't a coincidence.
通路[つうろ]:passage/pathway/roadway, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||
原川が通路を開いたんだ
Harakawa himself opened the passage!
つながる:to be tied together/to be connected to|to lead to
ダメだわ
うちもハラケンもつながんない
No way...
I can't connect to Haraken either.
メガばあは？
What about Mega-baa?
ダメだった
Nothing.
メール:email, 入れる[いれる]:to put in|to admit|to accept||
（フミエ）
じゃあ メール入れてみて
Then, try e-mail!
電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device), メール:email
電話がダメなのに
メールはできるの？
Will e-mail work if the telephone doesn't?
メール:email, サーバー:server
（フミエ）ダメもとよ
メールはサーバーが別だからね
It's worth a try.
E-mail uses a different server.
事態[じたい]:situation/(present) state of affairs/circumstances, 打開[だかい]:break in the deadlock
こんな事態を打開できるのは
メガばあだけだわ
Mega-baa is the only one who can find a way out of this.
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken, 辺り[あたり, ほとり]:on the bank of|(in the) neighbourhood|around (Sunday, last year, etc...)|
（イサコ）確か この辺りのはずだ
It should be around here.
無事[ぶじ]:safety/peace/quietness
無事か
So he's all right.
考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||
考えすぎだったか
I'm just thinking too much.
Amasawa!
As I thought!
やっぱり:too/also|still
やっぱり…
今 行くから そこで待ってて
I'm coming. Wait there a sec!
体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||
（イサコ）体は もういいのか？
Is your body all right now?
Yeah.
約束[やくそく]:promise|convention|destiny, 破る[やぶる]:to tear|to break through (cordon, opponent's defense, etc.)|to defeat||
約束 破ってすまない
Sorry... for breaking the promise.
あんな:such (about something or someone distant from both speaker and listener, or about a situation unfamiliar to both speaker and listener)/so/that, あんな:Anna or Anwa era (968.8.13-970.3.25), 取り引き[とりひき]:transactions/dealings/business, そもそも:in the first place/to begin with|... the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")
いや あんな取り引き
そもそもするべきじゃなかった
Don't worry.
After all, I shouldn't have done that trade.
くだる:to descend/to go down|to be handed down (of an order, judgment, etc.), 望み[のぞみ]:wish/desire|prospect, 捨てる[すてる]:to throw away|to abandon|to give up
お前も くだらない望みは捨てろ
You have to throw away your vain hope.
あっち:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener), なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, 都市[とし]:town/city/municipal, 伝説[でんせつ]:tradition/legend/folklore
あっちなんて ただの都市伝説だ
"The other side" is just an urban legend.
感ずる[かんずる]:to feel/to sense
感じたんだ
I felt it.
奥[おく]:inner part/inside/interior
あの奥にカンナがいる
At the bottom of that place...
Kanna is there.
If I go there,
あっち:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener), 必ず[かならず]:always/without exception/necessarily
あっちに行けば 必ず…
I'm certain I can...
近づく[ちかづく, ちかずく]:to approach/to draw near|to get acquainted with
もう近づくな
Don't go near it anymore.
二[に, ふた]:two, 二[アル]:two, 度[たび, たんび]:time (three times, each time, etc.)/times, 度[ど]:degree (angle, temperature, scale, etc.)|counter for occurrences and times|strength (of alcohol), 取り引き[とりひき]:transactions/dealings/business, 借り[かり]:borrowing/debt/loan, 返す[かえす]:to return (something)|to turn over|to pay back|
お前とは二度と取り引きしない
借りはあとで返す
I'll never trade with you again.
I'll pay my debt later.
どのみち:anyway/anyhow/at any rate
どのみち
もう僕には何もできない
Anyway,
I can't do anything more.
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 取り上げる[とりあげる]:to pick up|to adopt|to take away|
メガネをオバちゃんに
取り上げられちゃったから
My aunt confiscated my glasses.
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, ちょうど:exactly/precisely|as if, ちょうど:supplies/furniture/fixtures
メガネを？　なら ちょうどいい
Your glasses?
Well, that's just perfect.
全部[ぜんぶ]:all/entire/whole, 忘れる[わすれる]:to forget/to leave carelessly/to be forgetful of, メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 遊び[あそび]:playing|play (margin between on and off, gap before pressing button or lever has an effect), やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit
全部 忘れろ
もうメガネ遊びはやめるんだ
Forget about everything.
You have to stop playing with glasses.
メガネ:spectacles/glasses
さもないと メガネに殺されるぞ
Otherwise,
the glasses will kill you.
（ヤサコ）
ハラケン それに京子も…
Haraken...
and then Kyoko.
都市[とし]:town/city/municipal, 伝説[でんせつ]:tradition/legend/folklore, なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something, 現実[げんじつ]:reality/actuality/hard fact
これは都市伝説なんかじゃない
現実だわ
This isn't just an urban legend.
It's all real.
（フミエ）バ… バカ言わないでよ
Don't talk nonsense.
ネット:network, メガネ:spectacles/glasses, ばかり:only/merely|approximately
ネットでも
メガネばかりやってると―
Also on the net, they say that if you constantly use the glasses,
頭痛[ずつう]:headache, 体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, 痛み[いたみ]:pain/ache|damage, 感じる[かんじる]:to feel/to sense/to experience
頭痛や体の痛みを
感じるっていうじゃない？
you may get a headache or feel physical pain, right?
痛み[いたみ]:pain/ache|damage
痛み？
Pain?
心臓[しんぞう]:heart|guts|central part
そうよ
ほら ハラケンの心臓だって
Exactly!
Also Haraken's heart
病院[びょういん]:hospital, 診る[みる]:to examine (medically), もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
病院で診てもらって
なんともなかったんでしょ？
was examined several times, and they found nothing, right?
でも それは…
But that's...
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 世界[せかい]:the world|sphere|renowned|
メガネの世界が―
There's no way the world of glasses could influence
現実[げんじつ]:reality/actuality/hard fact, 影響[えいきょう]:influence/effect|to influence, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
現実に影響するなんて
あるはずないわ
the real world.
ちゃんと:diligently/seriously|perfectly, 髪の毛[かみのけ]:hair (head), 拭く[ふく]:to wipe/to dry
京子ちゃんだって
ちゃんと髪の毛 拭かないから―
Also Kyoko
didn't dry her hair.
風邪をひく[かぜをひく]:to catch a cold, 決まる[きまる]:to be decided/to be settled|to look good in (clothes)
風邪をひいたに決まってる
That must be why she caught a cold.
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 外す[はずす]:to unfasten|to remove|to leave|
メガネ外しましょ
Let's take our glasses off.
今すぐ
Now, immediately.
大げさ[おおげさ]:grandiose/exaggerated, 考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||
ヤ… ヤサコは
大げさに考えすぎなのよ
Yasako, you definitely think way too much.
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 外す[はずす]:to unfasten|to remove|to leave|
だから ここはスパーンと
みんなでメガネ外してさ
So now, let's take our glasses off together, and...
イマーゴ:imago
イマーゴ…
（フミエ）えっ？
Imago.
Huh?
イマーゴ:imago
イマーゴってあったわよね？
There's this Imago thing.
考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||, 電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 世界[せかい]:the world|sphere|renowned|, 反映[はんえい]:reflection (light, image, situation, attitude, etc.)/reflecting|influence
考えたことを
電脳の世界に反映させるっていう
When you think of something, it causes a projection in cyberspace.
逆[ぎゃく]:reverse|converse (of a hypothesis, etc.)|inverse (function), 逆[さか]:inverse/reverse
もし その逆があったら？
If by some chance the reverse is also true...
イリーガル:illegal, 変[へん]:strange|unexpected|change||, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease
もし あのイリーガルや
あの変な空間が―
If...
those Illegals and that weird Space
イマーゴ:imago, 通ずる[つうずる]:to be open (to traffic)|to flow (liquid, current)|to be understood||, 意識[いしき]:consciousness|awareness|mano-vijnana (mental consciousness, cognizer of sensory information), 連れ去る[つれさる]:to take away/to kidnap
イマーゴを通じて
人の意識を連れ去るんだとしたら…
could rob people of their consciousness through Imago...
やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit
やめて！
Stop it!
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 世界[せかい]:the world|sphere|renowned|, 起こる[おこる]:to occur/to happen, たって:strongly hoping or requesting (of something that is difficult to be brought to fruition), たって:even if/even though|however, 映像[えいぞう]:reflection|video|image in one's mind
メガネの世界で何が起こったって
ただの映像よ
Whatever happens in the world of glasses
is just a graphic image!
No kid attacked by Satchii ever died!
攻撃[こうげき]:attack/strike|criticism, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
サッチーに攻撃されて
死んだ子なんていないわ
同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway
それと同じよ
Think about it!
証明[しょうめい]:proof/verification/certification, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
いいわ 証明してあげる
Okay then.
I'll prove it to you.
Eh?
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 外す[はずす]:to unfasten|to remove|to leave|
私 メガネ外すわ
I'll take my glasses off.
付き合う[つきあう]:to associate with/to keep company with|to go along with
付き合ってらんない
I can't stand it anymore.
バカバカしい:absurd/ridiculous/silly, 外す[はずす]:to unfasten|to remove|to leave|
バカバカしい… 外すわよ
It's so foolish.
I'll take them off.
（ヤサコ）待って
Wait.
何よ
What?
都市[とし]:town/city/municipal, 伝説[でんせつ]:tradition/legend/folklore
もし 都市伝説が…
If the urban legend...
あっち:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener), 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc., たとする:to appreciate/to be thankful
あっちの話が本当だったとしたら…
If the stories about "the other side"
are true...
信ずる[しんずる]:to believe/to believe in/to place trust in
し… 信じない
I don't believe it.
（ヤサコ）フミエちゃん 私…
Fumie, I...
ズレる:to slide/to slip off/to get dislocated
（フミエ）ズレてる
You're shifting!
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, イリーガル:illegal, 触る[さわる]:to touch/to feel
（ヤサコ）さっき
あのイリーガルに触られたの
An Illegal touched me then.
そしたら…
That's why.
そんなの…
That's absurd...
とても:very/awfully|(not) at all, 感じがする[かんじがする]:to have a feeling (that)/to have a sensation (that)
（ヤサコ）あのとき
とてもイヤな感じがしたの
At that moment,
I had a very bad feeling.
怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid
怖いような
Like a scary feeling.
悲しい[かなしい]:sad/sorrowful, 気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|
そう 悲しい…
悲しい気持ちになって
Yes, a sad...
A sad feeling.
幻覚[げんかく]:hallucination/illusion
（フミエ）そんなの幻覚よ
It's just a hallucination!
That black hole...
黒い[くろい]:black|dark|illicit, 穴[あな]:hole|deficit|vacancy||, 穴[けつ]:ass|rear|acupuncture point|, イリーガル:illegal
（ヤサコ）
あの黒い穴 人型のイリーガル
Those human-shaped Illegals...
きっと:surely/undoubtedly|sternly, 都市[とし]:town/city/municipal, 伝説[でんせつ]:tradition/legend/folklore, 以上[いじょう]:not less than|beyond ... (e.g. one's means)|above-mentioned||
きっと何かあるんだわ
都市伝説以上の何かが…
I'm certain something's there.
Something deeper than urban legends.
じゃあ あいつらは
オバケか何かで―
So, you mean that if they touch you,
like, with a trick, you would die!?
触る[さわる]:to touch/to feel, じゃう:to do something completely
触られたら死んじゃうわけ？
なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
それで死んだ人なんて聞いたこと…
I never heard of someone dying because of that!
カンナは…
Kanna...
カンナは死んだわ
did die.
だって それは…
But....
That's...
外す[はずす]:to unfasten|to remove|to leave|
フミエちゃんは外していいよ
（フミエ）えっ？
Fumie, you can take yours off.
多分[たぶん]:perhaps/probably|generous, イリーガル:illegal, 触る[さわる]:to touch/to feel
多分 あのイリーガルに
触られてないし…
Maybe.
You weren't touched by that Illegal.
外す[はずす]:to unfasten|to remove|to leave|
私は外さない
I won't take mine off.
電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, 取り戻す[とりもどす]:to take back/to regain/to get back
京子の電脳体を取り戻すまで
Not until Kyoko's cyberbody comes back.
Oh, right!
そうだ
That's right!
気がつく[きがつく]:to notice|to be scrupulous|to recover consciousness
そうだよ
なんで気がつかなかったんだろう
Why didn't I realize this before?
If it's just to use the terminal...
単なる[たんなる]:mere/simple/sheer, 端末[たんまつ]:terminal|information access device (smartphone, tablet, book-reader, etc.)|end (e.g. of a roll of film), 機能[きのう]:function/facility/faculty, ログイン:login
単なる端末機能だけなら
僕の名前でログインできるはずだ
I should be able to log in under my name!
Logged successfully!
It worked!
うまい:skillful/skilful|delicious
うまくいった
黒い[くろい]:black|dark|illicit, メタタグ:META tag
（フミエ）んで 黒かったのね？
そのメタタグ
So it was a black metatag, right?
Yup, it made Haraken's cyberbody come back.
電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, 元に戻す[もとにもどす]:to go back to the start/to reset/to restore
（ヤサコ）うん
ハラケンの電脳体を元に戻したの
It looks like it's not here.
みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
ここにはないみたいね
Maybe that Illegal was Miss Michiko?
イリーガル:illegal, かしら:I wonder, かしら:head|hair (on one's head)
あのイリーガルが
ミチコさんなのかしら？
Cut it out!
やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit
（フミエ）やめてよ
結界[けっかい]:(fixing) boundaries for religious practices|prohibition (of items, people, spirits, etc. that would hinder Buddhist practice)|fence between inner and outer sanctums in a temple||, 破る[やぶる]:to tear|to break through (cordon, opponent's defense, etc.)|to defeat||, 気[き]:spirit|nature|motivation||, 気[げ]:seeming/giving the appearance of/giving one the feeling of
あいつら 結界を破る気だわ
Those guys...
They're trying to break the barrier!
連絡[れんらく]:to contact|contacting|connection|, 取れる[とれる]:to come off|(of pain, a fever, etc.) to disappear|to be caught||
ああ～ メガばあと
連絡さえ取れれば…
Ah,
if we could only contact Mega-baa...
昔[むかし]:olden days/former, 電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device)
こ… これ
（ヤサコ）昔の電話だわ
What's this?!
It's an old-fashioned telephone!
使える[つかえる]:to be usable/to be serviceable/to be useful
まだ使えるの？
Does it still work?
Yes?
ハロー:halo
（メガばあ）
ハロー わしじゃよ
Hello!
It's me!
おばば！
（フミエ）マジ？
Granny!
Really?!
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device), つながる:to be tied together/to be connected to|to lead to
（ヤサコ）よかった
メガネの電話がつながらなかったの
Thank goodness!
My glasses telephone wouldn't go through!
電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device), 特別[とくべつ]:special, 製[せい]:-made/make
（メガばあ）この電話は特別製でな
This telephone is peculiar.
大変[たいへん]:very|immense|serious||
おばば 京子が… 京子が大変なの！
Granny! Kyoko...
Kyoko is in big trouble!
Is there a way to save her?
助ける[たすける]:to save|to help|to aid|, 方法[ほうほう]:method/process/manner
助ける方法はないの？
黒い[くろい]:black|dark|illicit, メタタグ:META tag
（メガばあ）ある
コイルタグという黒いメタタグじゃ
There is. The black metatag called Coil-Tag.
黒い[くろい]:black|dark|illicit, メタタグ:META tag
黒いメタタグ？
Black metatag?
やっぱり:too/also|still
やっぱり
オバちゃんが使ってたやつだ
It must be the one Aunty was using!
玉子[たまご]:eggs|hen egg|(an expert) in the making|, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||
（メガばあ）玉子(たまこ)が？
わししか作れんはずじゃが…
Tamako?
I thought I was the only one who could create it.
それで どこにあるの？
And where is it?
工事[こうじ]:construction work/construction/work (related to construction, e.g. painting, concrete-pouring, etc.), 現場[げんば, げんじょう]:actual spot/scene|shop floor, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
（フミエ）オヤジがいれば
前の工事現場みたいに―
If only I had Oyaji with me,
we could send him to help her right away, like back then in the construction ground!
助け[たすけ]:assistance/help/aid, 行[ぎょう]:line (i.e. of text)|carya (austerities)|samskara (formations)|, 行[こう]:going|type of classical Chinese verse (usu. an epic)|district (of similar merchants)|
すぐ助けに行けたのに…
結ぶ[むすぶ]:to tie|to bear (fruit)|to close (e.g. deal)||
ほら 結んだわ
Okay, I tied it.
空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, きっと:surely/undoubtedly|sternly
（ヤサコ）あのときの空間とは
きっと違うわ
It's a different Space from the other time.
（フミエ）なんで分かるのよ？
How do you know?
（ヤサコ）なんとなくだけど…
It's just a feeling, but...
やっぱり:too/also|still
やっぱり 私も行くわ
I can't let you go alone!
フミエちゃんは
京子を見ててくれないと
Fumie, you have to look after Kyoko.
怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid
（フミエ）ヤサコ 怖くない？
Yasako, aren't you scared?
怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid
怖いわ 死ぬほど
I am scared.
Scared to death.
お願い[おねがい]:request/wish|please
京子をお願い
Take care of Kyoko.
カウンター:counter, 枚[まい]:counter for flat objects (e.g. sheets of paper), 枚[びら, ビラ]:bill/handbill/flier
（メガばあ）
コイルタグはカウンターの中に
１枚だけあるはずじゃ
There should be only one Coil-Tag, on the counter.
貼る[はる]:to stick|to stretch|to form (e.g. ice on a pond)||, 元[もと]:origin|base|cause||, 元[げん]:unknown (e.g. in an equation)|element (of a set)|yuan (monetary unit of China)|, 戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
（フミエ）
それを貼れば元に戻るのね？
So if we apply it, she should go back to normal, right?
簡単[かんたん]:simple/easy|brief, 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
（メガばあ）
そう簡単な話ではないのじゃ
It's not that easy.
黒い[くろい]:black|dark|illicit, メタタグ:META tag
（ヤサコ）黒いメタタグ…
Black metatag...
暗い[くらい]:dark|dark (in colour)|depressed||
暗くて よく分からない
It's so dark I can't tell which is which.
急ぐ[いそぐ]:to hurry/to rush/to hasten
急がないと…
I gotta hurry.
No!
イヤ！
どういう:somehow/how/in what way, 貼る[はる]:to stick|to stretch|to form (e.g. ice on a pond)||
（フミエ）どういうこと？
コイルタグを貼れば―
What do you mean?
Isn't attaching this Coil-Tag enough to make Kyoko return to normal?
元[もと]:origin|base|cause||, 元[げん]:unknown (e.g. in an equation)|element (of a set)|yuan (monetary unit of China)|, 戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
京子ちゃんは
元に戻るんじゃないの？
電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, 薄い[うすい]:thin|pale|watery||
（メガばあ）京子の電脳体
薄くなっておらんか？
Isn't Kyoko's cyberbody becoming translucent?
（フミエ）あっ なってるわ
It is...
あっち:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener), ウロウロ:loiteringly/aimless wandering/restlessly
（メガばあ）京子のヤツ
あっちでウロウロしてるうちに
While Kyoko is wandering around "the other side,"
距離[きょり]:distance/range, 開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
距離が開いてしまっておるのじゃ
she's creating a gap.
開く[ひらく]:to open|to bloom|to open (for business, e.g. in the morning)||, 開く[あく]:to open (e.g. doors)|to open (e.g. business, etc.)|to be empty||
開くと どうなるの？
And what happens with this gap?
リンク:link/directory entry, たどれる:to follow (road)/to pursue (course)/to follow up, 戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
（メガばあ）
リンクをたどれなくなる
つまり戻ってこられなくなる
Linking back becomes impossible.
In other words, she won't be able to come back anymore.
なんですって？
What?!
近距離[きんきょり]:short distance, 使える[つかえる]:to be usable/to be serviceable/to be useful
（メガばあ）
コイルタグは近距離でしか使えん
The Coil-Tag is effective only at close distances.
くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that
（フミエ）どのくらいよ！
How close?
メートル:metre/meter, くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that
（メガばあ）
３メートルくらいじゃ
About three meters.
メートル:metre/meter
３メートル？
Three meters?!
距離[きょり]:distance/range, 電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, 導く[みちびく]:to guide/to lead|to derive
（メガばあ）その距離まで
京子の電脳体を導くのじゃ
Within that distance, it guides Kyoko's cyberbody back.
導く[みちびく]:to guide/to lead|to derive, 一体[いったい]:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")|one object|one form||
“導くのじゃ”って…
一体どうやってよ？
Guides,
you say?
考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||
（メガばあ）それは 今 考え中じゃ
I'm...
still thinking about that.
Mega-baa!
メガばあ！
じゃが:potato (Solanum tuberosum), 思い出す[おもいだす]:to recall/to remember/to recollect
（メガばあ）
じゃが 思い出してきたわい
I just remembered!
現象[げんしょう]:phenomenon, イリーガル:illegal
この現象
そして あのイリーガル…
This phenomenon...
And then, about these Illegals...
Give me.
（ヌル）チョウダイ…
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
ここは…
This place?
ここ 知ってる
I know this place...
（フミエ）
メガばあ なんとかできないの？
Mega-baa! Is there something we can do?
可能性[かのうせい]:potentiality/likelihood/possibility, 低い[ひくい]:low (rank, degree, value, content, quality, etc.)|low (position)|short (height)|, 電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device), かける:to hang (e.g. picture)/to hoist (e.g. sail)|to sit, かける:to run (race, esp. horse)/to dash|to gallop (one's horse)
（メガばあ）うむ… そうじゃ！
可能性は低いが電話かけてみい
Right. There's only a slight chance, but try to phone her.
電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device)
電話？
Phone?
You have to call Kyoko's glasses-phone number.
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 番号[ばんごう]:number/series of digits, 電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device)
（メガばあ）京子のメガネ番号に
電話するのじゃ
電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device), 電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, 体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||
電話は電脳体のほうに…
The telephone and her cyberbody are-
ちょ… ちょっと何よ 今の
H-Hey, what were you about to say?
円[えん]:yen/Japanese monetary unit|circle, 円[まる]:circle|entirety|money||, 玉[たま]:ball|bead (of sweat, dew, etc.)|ball (in sports)||, 玉[ぎょく]:precious stone (esp. jade)|egg (sometimes esp. as a sushi topping)|stock or security being traded||, なくなる:to die, なくなる:to be lost (e.g. luggage)/to be missing|to be used up, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
（メガばあ）すまん
10円玉がなくなってしもう…
Sorry! My ten yen are about to-
Me...
Mega-baa!
メガばあ！
着信[ちゃくしん]:arrival (e.g. post, signal)|receiving/incoming, 履歴[りれき]:personal history|log|hysteresis, かける:to hang (e.g. picture)/to hoist (e.g. sail)|to sit, かける:to run (race, esp. horse)/to dash|to gallop (one's horse), 直す[なおす]:to cure|to fix|to do over again (after -masu base of verb)||
そうだ 着信履歴から かけ直せば…
Right!
If I call back from the call history list...
えっと:let me see/well/errr ..., かしら:I wonder, かしら:head|hair (on one's head)
えっと… あれ どこかしら？
Err...
Oh?
Where is it?
わあっ！
Yasako, stop appearing from creepy places!
変[へん]:strange|unexpected|change||, 現れる[あらわれる]:to appear/to come in sight|to be expressed (e.g. emotions)
ヤサコ 変なとこから現れないでよ
Sorry,
ご… ごめん
but I didn't know I'd come out here.
場所[ばしょ]:place|room|basho, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
こんな場所に出るなんて
知らなかったの
There's a secret passage that links to the Megashi store.
屋[や]:(something) shop|somebody who sells (something) or works as (something)|somebody with a (certain) personality trait||, 間[あいだ, あわい]:space (between)|time (between)|span (temporal or spatial)||, 間[ま]:time|space|room, 隠す[かくす]:to hide/to conceal, 廊下[ろうか]:corridor/hallway/passageway
メガシ屋との間に隠し廊下があるの
隠す[かくす]:to hide/to conceal, 廊下[ろうか]:corridor/hallway/passageway
隠し廊下？
A secret passage?
フミエちゃん これ
Fumie, these!
ハァ… コイルタグは？
The Coil-Tag?
Here it is!
あったわ
Oh! Mega-baa said something strange!
変[へん]:strange|unexpected|change||
そうだ
メガばあが変なこと言ってたわ
Strange?
変[へん]:strange|unexpected|change||
（ヤサコ）変なこと？
Come on,
食べる[たべる]:to eat|to live on (e.g. a salary)/to live off
（ヌル）さあ お食べ
eat.
Kyoko?
（ヤサコ）京子？　京子なの？
Is this Kyoko?
Sis?
お姉ちゃん[おねえちゃん]:familiar form of "older sister"|form of address for young adult female
お姉ちゃん？
It worked!
つながる:to be tied together/to be connected to|to lead to
つながった！
Kyoko,
いける:to arrange (flowers)/to plant|living, いける:to be good (at)/to go well|to look (taste, etc.) good, 場所[ばしょ]:place|room|basho
京子 そこは
いちゃいけない場所なの
you're in a place where you mustn't be!
You have to come back!
戻ってくる[もどってくる]:to come back
戻ってくるのよ
Where are you now?
今 どこにいるの？
I don't know.
（京子）分かんない
It's a festival!
お祭り[おまつり]:festival/feast/carnival
お祭りやってるよ
A festival?
お祭り[おまつり]:festival/feast/carnival
（ヤサコ）お祭り？
We're hearing her voice even though her mouth isn't moving!
口[くち]:mouth|opening|mouth (of a bottle)||, 口[く, こう]:mouth/speech|counter for people or implements, 動く[うごく]:to move|to operate|to be touched||, 電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device), 声[こえ]:voice, 聞こえる[きこえる]:to be heard/to be audible|to be said to be
口が動かないのに
電話から声が聞こえるわ
What kind of place is it?
どんな:what/what kind of|(with -temo, demo, etc.) any(body, thing, means, etc.), 場所[ばしょ]:place|room|basho
どんな場所なの？
There are a lot of booths...
いっぱい:one defeat, いっぱい:amount necessary to fill a container (e.g. cupful, spoonful, etc.)/drink (usu. alcoholic)|full, お店[おたな]:merchant's home (esp. used by apprentices, etc.)|(your) rental home
（京子）いっぱいお店がある―
and stairs with torii.
鳥居[とりい]:torii/Shinto shrine archway, 階段[かいだん]:stairs/stairway/staircase
鳥居の階段だよ
Kyoko,
階段を上る[かいだんをのぼる]:to go up the stairs
京子 その階段を上ってはダメよ
you must not climb those stairs!
You have to go back the way you came!
道[みち]:road|distance|the way (of proper conduct, etc.)||, 道[どう]:road|way|Buddhist teachings||, 戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
来た道を戻るのよ
いい？　聞いて
Listen!
All those things you're seeing are just illusions!
見える[みえる]:to be seen|to look|to come, 見える[まみえる]:to have an audience|to face (an enemy)|to serve (esp. as one's wife), 全部[ぜんぶ]:all/entire/whole
そっちで見えているものは
全部ウソなの
Get away from those stairs!
階段[かいだん]:stairs/stairway/staircase, 下りる[おりる]:to descend (e.g. a mountain)|to alight (e.g. from bus)|to step down||
その階段から下りるのよ
An old-timer gave me some candy.
おじちゃんがアメをくれたの
Kyoko!
捨てる[すてる]:to throw away|to abandon|to give up, 逃げる[にげる]:to escape/to run away
京子 アメを捨てて逃げて
Throw the candy away and get out of there!
Quickly!
早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|
早く！
Give me.
Run!
逃げる[にげる]:to escape/to run away
逃げて！
Give me.
（ヌルたち）
チョウダイ… チョウダイ…
Give me.
Densuke!
（京子）デンスケ
Give me.
ワン？
デンスケだ！　デンスケがいる
It's Densuke! Densuke's there!
静か[しずか]:quiet|slow|calm
静かに
Be quiet.
声[こえ]:voice, 方向[ほうこう]:direction/orientation|course (e.g. of action), 走る[はしる]:to run|to travel (movement of vehicles)|to hurry to||
京子 デンスケの声のする方向に
走るのよ！
Kyoko!
Run towards Densuke's voice.
切れる[きれる]:to break|to be injured|to wear out||
（フミエ）どうしたの？
（ヤサコ）切れたわ
What happened?
The line is dead.
お姉ちゃん[おねえちゃん]:familiar form of "older sister"|form of address for young adult female
お姉ちゃん お姉ちゃん！
Sis! Sis!
（ヌルたち）
チョウダイ… チョウダイ…
Give me.
ウンチ！
Poop!
一度[いちど, ひとたび]:once|temporarily|one degree, 電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device)
もう一度 電話を…
Let's call again...
フミエちゃん！
Fumie!
壁[かべ, へき]:wall|barrier|Chinese "Wall" constellation (one of the 28 mansions)
壁が…
The wall is...
部屋[へや]:room|apartment|stable
この部屋はもうダメよ
This room isn't safe anymore!
こっち
Here!
チョウダイ…
Give me.
あっ デンスケ！
Densuke!
一体[いったい]:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")|one object|one form||
（フミエ）ここ 一体なんなの？
What...
is this place?
建てる[たてる]:to build/to construct, 昔[むかし]:olden days/former, 家[いえ]:house|family|lineage, 家[うち, ち]:house/home (one's own)|(one's) family
（ヤサコ）よく分からない
おじじが建てた昔の家で…
I'm not really sure.
It's a house my Grandpa built a long time ago.
小さい[ちいさい]:small/little/tiny, ことがある:(something) has occurred/to have done (something)|(something) happens on occasions
でも小さいとき来たことがある
But, I came here once when I was little.
隠す[かくす]:to hide/to conceal, 廊下[ろうか]:corridor/hallway/passageway
隠し廊下ね
A secret passage...
変[へん]:strange|unexpected|change||
でも 何か変よ
But...
something is strange.
廊下[ろうか]:corridor/hallway/passageway, 続く[つづく]:to continue|to continue (without a break)|to occur again and again||
この廊下 どこまで続いてるの？
Where does this passage lead?
まさか:by no means/never!|something unexpected
（ヤサコ）まさか…
Can it be...
何よ あれ？
What is that?!
やっぱり:too/also|still, 古い[ふるい]:old (not person)/aged/ancient, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease
（ヤサコ）
やっぱり これは古い空間だわ
As I thought...
It's obsolete Space!
Obsolete Space?
古い[ふるい]:old (not person)/aged/ancient, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease
古い空間？
ヤサコ？
Yasako...
どうしたの？　ヤサコ
What's wrong?
聞こえる[きこえる]:to be heard/to be audible|to be said to be
聞こえる
I can hear her!
声[こえ]:voice
京子の声だ
It's Kyoko's voice!
まさか:by no means/never!|something unexpected, 古い[ふるい]:old (not person)/aged/ancient, 空間[くうかん]:space/room/airspace, 空間[あきま]:vacancy/room for rent or lease, 同士[どうし, どし]:fellow/mutual/companion, つながる:to be tied together/to be connected to|to lead to
まさか 古い空間同士が
つながってるの？
Is it possible...
that the two obsolete Spaces are connected?!
京子！　デンスケ！　こっちよ！
Kyoko!
Densuke!
Here!
見て！
Look!
デンスケだわ！
（ヤサコ）京子！
It's Densuke!
Kyoko!
戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
京子！
（フミエ）戻ってきた！
Kyoko!
She came back!
コイルタグを！
The Coil-Tag!
京子
Kyoko...
It worked...
うまい:skillful/skilful|delicious
うまくいったわ
ヤバい:dangerous|awful|terrific
ヤサコ ヤバいよ
Yasako! We're in danger!
Where's the exit?
出口[でぐち]:exit/gateway/way out
出口はどこ？
Here!
屋[や]:(something) shop|somebody who sells (something) or works as (something)|somebody with a (certain) personality trait||
こっちよ
でも メガシ屋にもいるわ
They're also in the Megashi store!
強行[きょうこう]:forcing/enforcement|forced, 突破[とっぱ]:breaking through/breakthrough/penetration
強行突破しかないわ
All we can do is blast through!
行くわよ…
Let's go!
Preview
Next time
次回[じかい]:next time (occasion), 電脳[でんのう]:computer|cyberbrain/digital brain, コイル:coil
（ヤサコ）
次回 「電脳コイル」
on Dennou Coil:
Kanna and Yasako
〝カンナとヤサコ 〞
Kanna and Yasako.
See you next time.
楽しみ[たのしみ]:enjoyment/pleasure|anticipation
お楽しみに